**Current Address** Sharon, MA 02067

# James Shin jddshin@gmail.com US Citizen

Contact Info: (339) 364-4034

## **SUMMARY**

Polymer materials engineer with proven track record of product launches, formulation development and industrial scale-up experience. Chemical formulation experience comprises two-part polyurethanes, silicones, epoxies and acrylates. Analytical testing skills include mechanical, thermal, and chemical instruments. Experienced user of DOE and FMEA methodologies for engineering projects.

## **EDUCATION**

University of Texas at Austin, Austin, TX

2020 - Present

M.S. in Computer Science

The University of Akron, Akron, OH

M.S. in Polymer Engineering

Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, PA

**B.S.** in Materials Science and Engineering

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

<u>Instruments:</u> TGA, DMA, DSC, FTIR, SEM, XRD, AFM, GPC, EDS, Mechanical / Impact Testing, Internal / Double Planetary Mixing, Compression Molding, Rheometry, Ram/Profile/Screw Extrusion, High Shear Disperser, microCT, Additive Manufacturing

<u>General:</u> FMEA, JHA, HazMat, Wet Lab, Continuous Improvement, Lab/Pilot/Commercial Scaleup, Contract / Toll Manufacturing Relations

Applications/Languages: JMP, MS Office, QAD ERP, Minitab, SQL, Python

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

OPT Industries, Cambridge, MA

June 2020 – August 2021

#### Senior Polymer Developer

- Led materials development initiatives for a new proprietary 3D printing company spun off from MIT Media Lab
- Filed several patents covering novel chemistries for 3D printing
- Managed a team of scientists in developing 3D printing resins for high temperature, fatigue resistant and color matching applications
- Managed supplier relationships for successful scaleup and commercialization of in-house resin products

Align Technologies, San Jose, CA

July 2019 – February 2020

#### Senior 3D Process Engineer, Materials

- Served as lead engineer for additive manufacturing process development and transfer on Prefabricated Attachments project along with the Direct Fabrication Aligners project
- Performed scale-up activities across a disparate fleet of 3D printers
- Initiated product requirement studies including shelf life, pot life, batch-to-batch variability and supplier qualification in preparation for limited market release

Carbon, Inc., Redwood City, CA

July 2015 - July 2019

#### Senior Process Engineer, Materials

- Developer of Adidas Futurecraft 4D polymer resin platform utilizing Design of Experiments to rapidly screen and optimize material formulations for two-part polyurethanes
- Developer of UMA 90, a photopolymer with improved toughness and EH&S characteristics
- Formulated DPR 10, a photopolymer for Dental markets and a method for fine-tuning photocuring properties for extremely high accuracy specifications
- Conducted Design of Experiments to study effect of raw material variability on printability, and accelerate materials formulation work
- Installed Carbon's pilot scale mixing capabilities and performed equipment scoping activities
- Developed a constant color formulation theory for adidas Futurecraft 4D, reducing batch-to-batch color variability to below human perception thresholds

- Scaled resin production from 15kg per batch up to 5000kg per batch and trained technicians on manufacturing best practices
- Saved over \$600K by salvaging non-compliant product caused by CMO error
- Performed cycle time analysis on Futurecraft 4D production processes to reduce C/T, labor and derived necessary equipment specifications
- Actively discussed potential scale-up issues with Materials team, and coordinated with Quality to implement document control on critical process procedures, SOPs, and FMEAs
- Implemented 5S as an Area Lead for Carbon's main laboratory

## Laird - Performance Materials, Cleveland, OH

Aug 2013-July 2015

#### Process Engineer, Performance Materials Division

- Developed EcE118, a MIL-DTL Type-A silver/copper conductive silicone for military markets
- Formulated Form-In-Place silicone products to improve shipping stability in Asian markets
- Launched Non-Conductive-Elastomer products: NcE240, NcE241, NcE242 and NcE245
- Successfully scaled-up manufacturing capabilities of Form-In-Place products in Belgium and trained technicians in production, quality control and shipping procedures
- Reduced batch variability in Thermal product lines by tightening raw material specifications using Design Of Experiments
- Coordinated research activities in a multinational corporation comprising teams from China, Czech Republic, Belgium, and Mexico